Women's Club of Storrs Records
© 2011 University of Connecticut
Women's Club of Storrs Records.
undated, 1903-2008.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Women's Club of Storrs.
6.5 linear feet.
MSS19920028
The Women's Club of Storrs began as the College Club in 1903. The purpose of the club, as stated in the first club constitution, was to promote literary and social culture. Membership was open to women connected with the [University of Connecticut] faculty, and included a few women faculty and faculty wives. A new constitution adopted in 1917 changed the name to the Women's Club of Storrs, and offered membership to “any woman of the community interested in the aims of the club.”
History
The Women's Club of Storrs began as the College Club in 1903. The purpose of the club, as stated in the first club constitution, was to promote literary and social culture. Membership was open to women connected with the [University of Connecticut] faculty, and included a few women faculty and faculty wives. The first meeting was held 9 November 9 1903, and early meetings were held in member's homes. In January 1904 members voted to hold meetings in Grove Cottage.
The club's constitution was revised in 1904 to include “the instruction of the members through such course of reading and study as the club may select.” Eligibility for membership was broadened to include women in the community, and the club joined the State Federation of Women's Clubs in Connecticut.
By 1913 the club's name had been changed to the Book Club. A new constitution adopted in 1917 changed the name to the Women's Club of Storrs, and offered membership to “any woman of the community interested in the aims of the club.”
Scope and Content
The collection contains the working papers of the organization including minutes, reports, bulletins, yearbooks as well as photographs and newspaper clippings concerning the Club's activities. The yearbook (membership directory) of the organization is restricted for ten years from the date of publication.
Arrangement
The records of the Women's Club of Storrs covers the period from its inception in 1903 through 1992, with the bulk of material focusing on the years 1933-1989. The collection is arranged in four series.
Series I: Minutes ( 1903-2001 ) contains five bound volumes of Minutes of the General Meetings from 1903-1965 and folders from 1951-2001, as well as two bound volumes of Minutes of the Executive Board from 1951-1965 and eleven folders from 1951-1989. Both of these meetings were held monthly. The bound volumes of Executive Board Minutes also include copies of the first and revised constitutions and bylaws as well as club programs.
Series II: Bulletins and Yearbooks ( 1914-1986 ). The bulletins summarize the activities of all the club's groups and committees. Materials for 1933-1934 also contain newspaper clippings about club activities. The yearbooks, called programs before 1953-1954, cover the period from 1914-1986, with the bulk between 1950-1986. Yearbooks list club officers, meetings and programs for the year, department and committee chairpersons, honorary life members and former presidents.
Series III: Administrative Records ( undated, 1927-2001 ) houses a variety of club records. These records include annual meetings and reports, correspondence, membership lists, constitutions and bylaws, officer and chairmen lists, and committee information.
Series IV: Photographs And Newspaper Clippings ( 1955-1966 ) contains an album of photographs and newspaper clippings. They deal with club activities, the election of new officers, the awarding of scholarships, and speakers at club meetings.
Series V: Additions ( undated, 1953-2008 ) contains additions to the collection added after 2005.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of papers pertaining to the community and University's history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Women--United States--Societies and clubs.; Storrs (Conn.)--Societies, etc.--Women.
Document Types:
Notebooks.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Press releases.; Fliers [printed matter]; Notes.; Scrap-Books.
Occupations:
Social Organization.
Restrictions on Access
Access to the Yearbooks (membership directory) is restricted to WCOS members for ten years from the date of publication.
Acquisition Information
The records of the Women's Club of Storrs were donated to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives [HMA] Department (now Archives & Special Collections) of the University of Connecticut Libraries by the Mansfield Historical Society in 1992. Subsequent donations have been received from WCOS members periodically.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Minutes, 1903-2001
  - Executive Meetings, 1951-1953; (1 volume) (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - General Meetings, 1903-1923; (1 volume) (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - General Meetings, 1923-1935; (1 volume) (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - General Meetings, 1935-1953; (1 volume) (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - General Meetings, 1953-1965; (1 volume) (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - General Meetings, 1951-1986 (Box 1:, Folder 6-13)
  - General Meeting, 2001 (Box 1:, Folder 105)
  - Executive Meetings, 1928-1951; (1 volume) (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - Executive Meetings, 1953-1965; (1 volume) (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Executive Meetings, 1951-1959 (Box 2:, Folder 16-18)
  - General Meetings, 1951-1986 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Executive Meetings, 1960-1989 (Box 3:, Folder 20-27)
- Series II: Bulletins and Yearbooks, 1914-1986
  - Bulletins, 1933-1955 (Box 4:, Folder 28-49)
  - Bulletins, 1956-1974 (Box 5:, Folder 50-63)
  - Bulletins, 1975-1989 (Box 6:, Folder 69)
  - Yearbooks, 1914-1915, 1917-1918, 1924-1925, 1946-1947 1947-1948 (Box 6:, Folder 70)
  - Yearbooks, 1950-1951, 1952-1953 (Box 6:, Folder 71)
  - Yearbooks, 1953-1954, 1960-1961 (Box 6:, Folder 72)
  - Yearbooks, 1961-1962, 1962-1963 (Box 6:, Folder 73)
  - Yearbooks, 1963-1964, 1965-1966 (Box 6:, Folder 74)
  - Yearbooks, 1966-1967, 1967-1968 (Box 6:, Folder 75)
  - Yearbooks, 1968-1969 (Box 6:, Folder 76)
  - Yearbooks, 1969-1970, 1971-1972 (Box 6:, Folder 77)
  - Yearbooks, 1972-1973, 1975-1976 (Box 6:, Folder 78)
  - Yearbooks, 1976-1977, 1977-1978 (Box 6:, Folder 79)
  - Yearbooks, 1978-1979, 1985-1986 (Box 6:, Folder 80)
- Series III: Administrative Records, undated, 1903-2001
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1948-1972, 1973, 1986 (Box 7:, Folder 81)
  - Annual Reports and Meetings, 1955-1980, 1982-1992 (Box 7:, Folder 82-86)
  - Annual Report, 2001 (Box 7:, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1979 (Box 7:, Folder 87-88)
  - Membership Lists, 1928-1983, 1987-1988 (Box 7:, Folder 89-90)
  - Parish House rules and regulations, undated (Box 8:, Folder 91)
  - Guest Book, 1958 (Box 8:, Folder 92)
  - Dues record-book and checklist, 1940-1949, 1991 (Box 8:, Folder 93)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1936-1938 (Box 8:, Folder 94)
  - Officers and chairmen lists/officer duties, 1903-1952, 1964-1965, 1969-1972 (Box 8:, Folder 95)
  - Library committee reports, 1936-1941 (Box 8:, Folder 96)
  - Drama group literary programs, 1959-1970 (Box 8:, Folder 97)
  - State tax returns, 1951-1960 (Box 8:, Folder 98)
  - Legislative program, undated (Box 8:, Folder 99)
  - Book passing group, undated (Box 8:, Folder 100)
  - Connecticut State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1941-1965 (Box 8:, Folder 101)
  - Activities, undated (Box 8:, Folder 102)
- Series IV: Photographs & Newspaper Clippings, 1955-1966
  - Photograph and newspaper clipping album, 1955-1966 (Box 9:, Folder 103)
- Series V: Additions, undated, 1953-2008
  - (Box 10)
    - Bulletin, 1953-1965
    - Bulletin, 1966-1971
    - Bulletin, 1971-1977
    - Bulletin, 1978-1982
    - Bulletin, 1989-2001
  - (Box 11)
    - Bulletin, 2001-2004
    - By Laws, 1990, 2001
    - Cookbook, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and notes, undated, 2005-2008
    - Eloise Trail file, 1985-2002
    - Reports, 2001-2003
    - Yearbook, 1953-1971
    - Yearbook, 1971-1985
    - Yearbook, 1985-2001
    - Small photograph album, undaated